ACTWU's Research Department Records 5619/016
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ACTWU's Research Department Records
1914-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. Research Department
Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union. Research Department
5619/016
102.5 cubic feet
102.5 linear feet
Correspondence, reports, publications.
This collection consists of correspondence, reports, newspaper clippings, and files from the Research Departments of the Textile Workers' Union of America, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union. A small, scattered selection of material dates from after the the ACTWU merger with the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). This material could not be easily separated out to be placed in the related UNITE collection, 6000/020, and was left in place.
6791834
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
December 2010
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 2011
Biographical / Historical
The Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, the most significant union representing workers in the men's clothing industry, was founded in New York City in 1914 as a breakaway movement from the United Garment Workers. Radical and immigrant workers in the tailors' and cutters' locals were the core of the seceding group, which advocated industrial unionism and economic strikes in opposition to the UGW's craft organization, which they saw as conservative and timid. Their diverging views had come to the fore during the historic 1910 dispute at the Chicago firm Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. The opposition called the strike against the UGW leadership's advice, and reached a path-breaking agreement with management that established an arbitration system to settle disputes.
Members flocked to the new union. Around 50,000 strong at its founding, by 1920 the ACWA counted about 170,000 members. Initially composed mostly of immigrants of Jewish European descent with Socialist leanings, the ACWA quickly welcomed members of a great number of nationalities and diverse backgrounds. Like in other garment unions, most workers and many members were women, but the leadership was predominantly male, a situation that did not change for many decades. Early on the union adopted a centralized administrative structure combined with industrial unionism, with the joint boards' by-laws having precedence over those of locals.
Espousing a philosophy perhaps brought over by its early immigrant socialist members, the Amalgamated went beyond bread and butter issues and adopted a distinctive form of social unionism that was largely absent in the American labor movement. Starting in the 1920s, it provided educational opportunities and recreational facilities for its members, as well as services such as an insurance plan, banks offering personal loans at low interest rates, low-cost housing cooperatives, medical clinics, and even union-owned restaurants.
Sidney Hillman was the first president of the new union and the most important officer in its history. He applied his experience as bargaining representative in Chicago to the whole industry. Under his leadership the union made significant strides in securing better wages and working conditions for its members, and at the same time it consolidated gains and provided stability to the industry through the widespread adoption of the arbitration system tested at Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. Hillman paid close attention to industry issues, such as production, pricing, and marketing. In order to help management meet the competition of non-union firms, the union conducted studies of efficiency, work methods, and factory costs. Letters to the official publication of the union, Advance, document the controversy that ensued within the union over what was perceived to be collaboration with management.
Hillman also understood the importance of labor's involvement in national affairs and political action. In the 1920s the ACWA sent delegates to the Conference for Progressive Political Action and to the Farmer-labor party conventions. Although many members and officers were Socialists, the union stopped short of officially endorsing the party. Communist attempts at gaining influence within the union were firmly curbed. Hillman's participation in national affairs and politics became prominent during the New Deal, when he became a close advisor to Franklin D. Roosevelt on labor and economic issues. He also served on the board of the National Recovery Administration. Later, during World War II, he helped establish the Labor's Non Partisan League. He was also named associate director of the Office of Production Management, which assisted in mobilizing the nation's resources for the war effort. Hillman's prestige perhaps reflected the healthy condition of his union, which by the end of the conflict was strong and stable.
During the post World War II period the union faced a number of significant challenges. Membership continued to grow (peaking at 395,000 in 1968), but the union's political influence and visibility in national affairs declined. In their never ending pursuit of lower production costs, many firms relocated to the South, forcing the union to engage in large organizing efforts. Simultaneously, signs began to appear of changes that would lead to the almost complete demise of the domestic apparel industry and, ultimately, to the erosion of union membership. Foreign imports of cheap clothing goods steadily grew in the 1950s and 1960s, and mushroomed in the following two decades, plunging employment in the apparel sector into a steady decline. Union efforts to stem the tide included Buy American campaigns and extensive lobbying in Congress, but they were to no avail. In 1976, the ACWA merged with the Textile Workers of America to become the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Despite successful and much publicized nationwide actions such as the Farah boycott and the J.P. Stevens corporate campaign, the woes threatening the union's existence continued unabated. The fate of the domestic industry was sealed in the late 1970s and the 1980s by the flight of firms chasing tax breaks and cheap labor abroad. By 1995, when ACTWU voted to merge with the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, their combined membership was 350,000. The new Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE!) seemed poised to infuse new life in a troubled union.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related collections: 5619: Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America 5619/012: ACTWU's Research Department Company Records 5619/013: ACTWU's Research Department Correspondence Chronological Files 5619/021: ACTWU's Research Department's Industrial Union Department Company Records All other 5619 collections 6000/003: UNITE's Research Department Historic Files 6000/014: UNITE's Research Department Correspondence Chronological Files and 6000/020: UNITE's Research Department Records
Textile workers -- Labor unions; Clothing workers -- Labor unions; Collective bargaining -- Clothing industry; Collective bargaining -- Textile industry; Plant shutdowns; Publications; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union. Research Dept.--Archives; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. Research Dept.--Archives; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Archives; Textile Workers Union of America; Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees; UNITE HERE (Organization) --Archives
6791834
- TWUA Research Department - Labor Relations Cases [Folder 1 of 3], 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- TWUA Research Department - Labor Relations Cases [Folder 2 of 3], 1950-1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- TWUA Research Department - Labor Relations Cases [Folder 3 of 3], 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Report on Agreements, Strikes, and Elections, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Report on Agreements, Strikes, and Elections, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Report on Agreements, Strikes, and Elections, 1964-1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Survey of TWUA Agreements, Elections, and Strikes, 1943-1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Survey of TWUA Agreements, Elections and Strikes, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Survey of TWUA Agreements, Elections and Strikes, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Survey of TWUA Agreements, Elections and Strikes, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Agreements and Elections (September 1949 - December 1949), Strikes (September 1949 - January 1950), 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Scope and Contents
  Report to The Executive Council Meeting January 16, 1950
- Biennial Survey of TWUA Agreements, Elections and Strikes, 1943-1948 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Biennial Survey of TWUA Agreements, Elections and Strikes, 1948-1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Biennial Survey of TWUA Agreements, Elections and Strikes, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- NAFTA AFL- CIO Report, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Received July 5, 1995 ACTWU Research Department
- New England & Mid-Atlantic - TEX- ANN. AVG, 1976-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- South Eastern - Factory Workers - AHE, 1964-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Unemployment Rates, By Industry, 1960-1977 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- New England - BWF - AHE, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  New England Average Hours and Earnings in Broad Woven Cotton: Wool Silk and Synthetics
- South Eastern Textile Plant Employment, 1977-1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- South Eastern - BWF - AHE, 1964- 1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  South Eastern Average Hours and Earnings in Broad Woven Cotton: Wool Silk and Synthetics
- Apparel Industry (SIC23), Employment By State, 1954-1995 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- American Apparel Industry Trends, 1980-1990 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Multi-Company Associates Under ACTWU Contract, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Charter of Fundamental Principles of Global Trade For Textiles and Apparel, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- ACWA Membership, 1915-1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- ACTWU-Statements, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- U.S.W. Plant Lists (United Shoe Workers of America), 1979-1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Plant Closings, 1968-1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- "Creating New Partnerships" Through Joint Cooperative Programs, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Textile Plant Liquidations: Non-South and South, 1970-1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Textile Industry Employment, By State, 1970-1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- UNITE Shops by State and Congressional District, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- UNITE Product Directory, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- UNITE Directory of Products Made By Our Members, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- UNITE Directory of Products Made By Former ILGWU Members, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- UNITE Directory of Products Made By Former ACTWU Members, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Brand Name Directory of Products Made by ACTWU Members, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- UNITE Bargaining Unit Directory, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- UNITE Bargaining Unit Directory, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- ACTWU Bargaining Unit Directory, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- ACTWU Bargaining Unit Directory, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- ACTWU Bargaining Unit Directory, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- ACTWU Bargaining Unit Directory, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- NAFTA - Congressional Research Service Studies, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- NAFTA - Newspaper Clips (Feb-May), 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- NAFTA - Economic Policy Institute Samples, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- NAFTA - Estimating the Effects of NAFTA, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- NAFTA - G.A.O. Report, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- NAFTA - Impact of NAFTA on Puerto Rico, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- NAFTA - International Labor Rights Education and Research Fund Report, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- NAFTA - International Trade Commission Samples, 1990-1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- NAFTA - Economy-Wide Modeling of the Economic Implications of NAFTA (May), 1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- NAFTA - Economy-Wide Modeling of the Economic Implications of A FTA with Mexico and A NAFTA with Canada and Mexico, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- NAFTA - Political Impact on the U.S Economy and Selected Industries of the NAFTA, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- NAFTA - Joint Economic Committee Staff Study, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- NAFTA - Latinos and NAFTA, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- NAFTA - Manufacturing Policy Project Study, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- NAFTA - Mercosur - Other FTA, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  English and Spanish
- NAFTA - Views from Mexico, 1989-1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- NAFTA - Monitor, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- NAFTA - NADBank, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- NAFTA - National Administration Office, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- NAFTA - Office of Technology Assessment Study, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- NAFTA - US - Mexico Trade: Pulling Together or Pulling Apart?, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- NAFTA - Papers - Senate Labor Committee and Human Resources Hearing, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- NAFTA - Plants moved to Mexico, 1982-1995 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- NAFTA - Side Agreements on Labor and Environment, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- NAFTA - Statements/ Testimonies, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- NAFTA - Trade Adjustments Assistance, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- NAFTA - USA - NAFTA (Business Lobbying Group), 1993 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- NAFTA - Views from Mexico (Gov/NonGov), 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- NAFTA - Women and NAFTA, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- ATI - America's Textiles International (September), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Authentic Labor Front (Box 4, Folder 2)
  El Frente Autentico De Trabajo (FAT)
- Canada and Latin American Integration, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Clinton's NAFTA Promises, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- The Connection between Mexican Labor Struggles and the Free Trade Agreement, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Cross Sections (Volume 10 Number 4 - Winter) Federal Reserve Bank of Richmond, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Economic Review (2Q) Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas - NAFTA, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- The Effect of NAFTA on Apparel Employment in the US (October), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Effect of the NAFTA on Investment, Employment and Wages in Mexico and the U.S. (February), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- The Enterprise for the Americas Initiative and the NAFTA: Consequences for the Caribbean Basin (February), 1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- First Annual United States - Mexico International Labor Law Conference (October 25-27), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Free Trade For Whom? The Impact of the U.S.- Mexican Free Trade Agreement On Labor, The Environment & Economic Development in NY State, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- 'Free' Trade's Hidden Secrets, Why We Are Losing Our Shirts, 1980 - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Goal of NAFTA is to integrate the economies of: Canada, United States, Mexico, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Immigration and Free Trade with Mexico: Protecting American Workers Against Double Jeopardy, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- In Stitches, U.S. Trade Office NAFTA Textiles and Apparel Executive Summary, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- In stitches, NAFTA New Age for Textiles and Apparel, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Industrial Modernization in Mexico, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Labor Advisory Committee on the NAFTA, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Monitoring Manufacturing Employment Trends in Chicago and Illinois: Implications for NAFTA Impacts, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- NAFTA, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- NAFTA, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- NAFTA: A Guide to Customs Procedure, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- NAFTA: An Early Assessment, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  A Report by the NAFTA Economic Monitoring Taskforce
- NAFTA and Apparel Imports from Mexico, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- NAFTA: Issues and Impact for Minnesota, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  Center for International Food and Agriculture Policy
- NAFTA: US Employment and Wage Effects, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- NAFTAmath - Midyear, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- NAFTA's Corporate Cadre - An Analysis of the USA*NAFTA State Captains, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- NAFTA's First Year Lessons for the Hemisphere, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- NAFTA - New Age for Textiles and Apparel, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- A North America Project Special Report, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- North America Free Trade Issues and Recommendations, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- North American Trade As If Democracy Mattered, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Preliminary Report of the Labor Advisory Committee for the Trade Negotiations and Trade Policy on the NAFTA, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Problems We Face in the Context of Economic Integration, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Report on the Americas: The New Gospel NAFTA, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- The Social Dimensions of North American Economic Integration, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- The Social Implications of NAFTA, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Study: U.S. - linked 'maquiladoras' proliferate, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- UAW Preliminary Analysis of Auto Sector NAFTA Negotiations, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- U.S. Citizens' Analysis of the NAFTA, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- U.S. Exports to Mexico - A State-by-State Overview 1987 and 1992, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- U.S. - Mexico Free Trade and the Mexican Garment Industry, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Various Statistics, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Amalgamated - Blogs, 1980-1990 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- ACWA - Biographies - DuChessi, William M., 1980 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- ACWA - Biographies - Joyce Miller, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- ACWA - Biographies - Sheinkman, Jacob, 1966-1987 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- ACTWU - Biographies Stetin, Sol, 1968-2000 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- ACWA - Biographies Swoboda, Peter, 1960-1973 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- ACTWU History (Box 4, Folder 52)
- AFL - CIO Resolutions and Statements, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- AFL - CIO Resolutions and Statements, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- ACTWU - Statements on Imports, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- ACWA Statements -- Imports, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Bemis Company, Inc. (IUD Study), 1966-1977 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- Jacob S. Potofsky Biographies - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1935-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Borden, Inc. (IUD Study), 1973-1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- The Equity Investment in America Program (Financing Opportunity for Post-Secondary Education in the U.S.), 1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Brunswick Corporation. (IUD Study), 1976-1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Building Products Committee (IUD Study), 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Celanese Corporation (IUD Study), 1967-1981 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- The Celotex Corporation, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Certain - Teed Products Corporation (IUD Study), 1965-1974 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- The ChinaTown Garment Industry Study, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Colgate - Palmolive Corporation (IUD Study), 1980 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Coordinated Bargaining Conference (IUD Study), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Coordinated Bargaining General (IUD Study), 1973-1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Computer Progress. - II NLRB Results (IUD Study), 1965-1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Cost of Protection, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Developing a Union Agenda On Technology and Work Organization, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- EPC (Economic Policy Council): Global, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- EPC (Economic Policy Council): Plenary, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- EPC (Economic Policy Council): Steering CTE, 1986-1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- EPI (Economic Policy Institute): Alternatives, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- EPI (Economic Policy Institute): Labor Advisory Board, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- EPI (Economic Policy Institute): MEAD, 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- EPI (Economic Policy Institute): Monetary Policy/Financial Reform, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- EPI (Economic Policy Institute): New Horizons, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- EPI (Economic Policy Institute) Trade Initiative, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- EPI (Economic Policy Institute) Research Council, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Excelsior Capital Corporation, 1991-1993 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Fair Measure, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Fair Trade and the Future of the Clothing Industry. Jack Sheinkman Speech, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- EPI (Economic Policy Institute): High Tech Seminar, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Histadrut (National Committee for Labor Israel), 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Labor Experience of Frieda Schwenkmeyer (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Biography: Finley Murray (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Industrial Policy NYS, 1981-1992 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- International Trade - Foreign Trade: Union Policies, 1967-1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- IUD - Collectiv4 Bargaining Services Section - Report on Activities, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- IUD - Election Reports General, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- IUD - Synthetic Fiber Industry - Study, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Jewish Labor Committee, 1979-1995 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- EPI (Economic Policy Institute): Job Displacement and the Rural Worker, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Klein Study - Tailored Clothing Industry, National Clothing Industry Labor-Management Committee, INC., 1989 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Knitwear Industry Center, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Labor Unions - Textile Workers of America, 1939-1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Biography: Harry Lautman, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Labor Review New York, 1982-1994 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Managed Trade: IIE (Institute for International Economics), 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Men's Fashion Association of America, 1979-1994 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Midwest Center for Labor Research, 1987-1995 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Modernizing America's Industrial Base, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- The Modernization Forum, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Mujer Obrera, La, 1990-1994 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- New York City Apparel Industry, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- New York City Garment Center Study, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Obituaries for 1990 Convention (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Obituaries for 1993 Convention (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Port Authority Apparel Project, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- The Reality of World Trade in Textiles and Apparel, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Biography - Simon Louis, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Textile Trade - ILGWU Statements, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Textile Trade - Imports Under Section 807 - Caribbean Basin Initiative (CBI), 1987-1999 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- EPI (Economic Policy Institute): US-Mexico Free Trade Agreement, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Work and Technology Meeting for Union Researchers & Economists, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- IUD - Technology Working Group, 1986-1995 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Worker Rights in Export Processing Zones, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- ACTWU - Legislative Statements, 1961-1981 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- ACTWU - Trade Statements, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Testimony - NYC Garment Industry, 1978-1983 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- ACTWU - Statements - Beck, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America - Statements - Blumberg, Hyman, 1947-1964 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1939-1955 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America - Statements - Finley, Murray H., 1975 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America - Statements - Genis, Sander, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America - Statements - Gundersheim, Art, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America - Statements - Hollander, Louis, 1953-1957 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America - Statements - Miller, Abraham, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America - Statements - Vera Miller, 1967-1979 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America - Statements - NYS - Legislation Needed for Apparel Con Ed Before PSC, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 18)